{
  "title": "Spanish Vocab",
  "cards": [
    {
      "front": "Mediana",
      "back": "medium"
    },
    {
      "front": "Avergonzado",
      "back": "embarrassed"
    },
    {
      "front": "Solitario",
      "back": "lonely"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ayuda",
      "back": "help"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ganar",
      "back": "to win"
    },
    {
      "front": "Equipo",
      "back": "team"
    },
    {
      "front": "Competencia",
      "back": "competition"
    },
    {
      "front": "competir",
      "back": "to compete"
    },
    {
      "front": "competitivo",
      "back": "competitive"
    },
    {
      "front": "baloncesto",
      "back": "basketball"
    },
    {
      "front": "Alto",
      "back": "tall"
    },
    {
      "front": "Bajo",
      "back": "short"
    },
    {
      "front": "Quedarse",
      "back": "to stay"
    },
    {
      "front": "Descansar",
      "back": "to rest"
    },
    {
      "front": "Estoy asustado",
      "back": "im freaking out"
    },
    {
      "front": "Femenino",
      "back": "female"
    },
    {
      "front": "Masculino",
      "back": "male"
    },
    {
      "front": "Hielo",
      "back": "ice"
    },
    {
      "front": "Drogada",
      "back": "high"
    },
    {
      "front": "High",
      "back": "high"
    },
    {
      "front": "Bosque",
      "back": "forest"
    },
    {
      "front": "En interior",
      "back": "on the inside"
    },
    {
      "front": "En la superficie",
      "back": "on the surface"
    },
    {
      "front": "Setenta",
      "back": "seventy"
    },
    {
      "front": "Sesenta",
      "back": "sixty"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lanzar",
      "back": "to throw"
    },
    {
      "front": "Golpear",
      "back": "to slap"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un barco",
      "back": "ship"
    },
    {
      "front": "Orejas",
      "back": "ears"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cuello",
      "back": "neck"
    },
    {
      "front": "Morder",
      "back": "to bite (stem change)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Doler",
      "back": "to hurt"
    },
    {
      "front": "Bigote",
      "back": "mustache"
    },
    {
      "front": "Perezoso",
      "back": "lazy"
    },
    {
      "front": "Peludo",
      "back": "hairy/furry (body hair)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lampiño",
      "back": "hairless (the whole body)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Humilde",
      "back": "humble"
    },
    {
      "front": "Egoista",
      "back": "selfish"
    },
    {
      "front": "Egocentrico",
      "back": "ego centric"
    },
    {
      "front": "Adelante",
      "back": "ahead (location)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Llorar",
      "back": "to cry"
    },
    {
      "front": "Superar",
      "back": "to overcome"
    },
    {
      "front": "Griego",
      "back": "greek"
    },
    {
      "front": "Acercarse",
      "back": "to get closer (physically or emotionally)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Oler",
      "back": "to smell"
    },
    {
      "front": "Tiburón",
      "back": "shark"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ahogarse",
      "back": "to drown (in liquid)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Gritar",
      "back": "scream"
    },
    {
      "front": "Saltar",
      "back": "to jump"
    },
    {
      "front": "Botar",
      "back": "to throw away"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cortina de ducha",
      "back": "shower curtain"
    },
    {
      "front": "Demasiado",
      "back": "too much"
    },
    {
      "front": "Estirar",
      "back": "to stretch"
    },
    {
      "front": "La caminadora",
      "back": "treadmill"
    },
    {
      "front": "En todas partes",
      "back": "everywhere"
    },
    {
      "front": "Dos pares",
      "back": "two pairs"
    },
    {
      "front": "La recuperación",
      "back": "recovery"
    },
    {
      "front": "Meter la pata",
      "back": "to mess up / make a mistake"
    },
    {
      "front": "Pesimista",
      "back": "pessimistic"
    },
    {
      "front": "Optimista",
      "back": "optimistic"
    },
    {
      "front": "Iceberg",
      "back": "iceberg"
    },
    {
      "front": "Profundo",
      "back": "deep"
    },
    {
      "front": "El bosque",
      "back": "the forest"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lastimar",
      "back": "to hurt / injure"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un crucero",
      "back": "A cruise"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un tiburón",
      "back": "A shark"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ponerse feliz",
      "back": "To become happy"
    },
    {
      "front": "Hasta",
      "back": "Until / Up to"
    },
    {
      "front": "Hueso",
      "back": "Bone"
    },
    {
      "front": "Travieso",
      "back": "Naughty / Mischievous"
    },
    {
      "front": "Caer",
      "back": "To fall"
    },
    {
      "front": "48 horas",
      "back": "48 hours"
    },
    {
      "front": "Simple",
      "back": "Simple"
    },
    {
      "front": "Votar",
      "back": "To vote"
    },
    {
      "front": "La cortina de la ducha",
      "back": "Shower curtain"
    },
    {
      "front": "El bote de basura",
      "back": "Trash can"
    },
    {
      "front": "El motor",
      "back": "Engine"
    },
    {
      "front": "El taller",
      "back": "Workshop / Garage"
    },
    {
      "front": "Reparar",
      "back": "To repair"
    },
    {
      "front": "Mecánico",
      "back": "Mechanic"
    },
    {
      "front": "Bailarín",
      "back": "Dancer"
    },
    {
      "front": "Darse cuenta de",
      "back": "to realize"
    },
    {
      "front": "Enamorarse",
      "back": "To fall in love"
    },
    {
      "front": "Dejar plantado a alguien",
      "back": "To stand someone up"
    },
    {
      "front": "El futuro cercano",
      "back": "The near future"
    },
    {
      "front": "Él me escribió",
      "back": "He wrote to me"
    },
    {
      "front": "La segunda mitad",
      "back": "The second half"
    },
    {
      "front": "Gruñón",
      "back": "Grumpy"
    },
    {
      "front": "En lugar de...",
      "back": "Instead of..."
    },
    {
      "front": "Ir de compras",
      "back": "To go shopping"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un pájaro",
      "back": "A bird"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una piña",
      "back": "A pineapple"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un hoyo",
      "back": "A hole"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una pala",
      "back": "A shovel"
    },
    {
      "front": "La fibra",
      "back": "Fiber"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un humano",
      "back": "A human"
    },
    {
      "front": "Apagar",
      "back": "To turn off"
    },
    {
      "front": "Encender",
      "back": "To turn on"
    },
    {
      "front": "Quizás",
      "back": "Maybe / perhaps"
    },
    {
      "front": "Las alturas",
      "back": "Heights"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un globo",
      "back": "A balloon"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lastimarse",
      "back": "To get hurt"
    },
    {
      "front": "Sangrar",
      "back": "To bleed"
    },
    {
      "front": "Chocar",
      "back": "To crash / to collide"
    },
    {
      "front": "Peligroso",
      "back": "Dangerous"
    },
    {
      "front": "Seco",
      "back": "Dry"
    },
    {
      "front": "Mojado",
      "back": "Wet"
    },
    {
      "front": "Olvidar",
      "back": "To forget"
    },
    {
      "front": "Llevarse mal",
      "back": "To not get along"
    },
    {
      "front": "Llevarse bien",
      "back": "To get along"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lucir",
      "back": "To look / to show off"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una pareja",
      "back": "A couple / partner"
    },
    {
      "front": "Echar de menos",
      "back": "To miss (someone/something)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Probablemente",
      "back": "Probably"
    },
    {
      "front": "Las entrecejas",
      "back": "The space between eyebrows"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cejas",
      "back": "Eyebrows"
    },
    {
      "front": "Suave",
      "back": "Soft"
    },
    {
      "front": "Duro",
      "back": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "front": "Angosto",
      "back": "Narrow"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ancho",
      "back": "Wide"
    },
    {
      "front": "El cuchillo",
      "back": "Knife"
    },
    {
      "front": "La cuchara",
      "back": "Spoon"
    },
    {
      "front": "El tenedor",
      "back": "Fork"
    },
    {
      "front": "La roca",
      "back": "Rock"
    },
    {
      "front": "La mantequilla",
      "back": "Butter"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ir de fiesta",
      "back": "To party / go partying"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un diario",
      "back": "A journal"
    },
    {
      "front": "No hay límites",
      "back": "There are no limits"
    },
    {
      "front": "Las características",
      "back": "Features / characteristics"
    },
    {
      "front": "Útil",
      "back": "Useful"
    },
    {
      "front": "Las desventajas",
      "back": "Disadvantages"
    },
    {
      "front": "Las ventajas",
      "back": "Advantages"
    },
    {
      "front": "Entrenador",
      "back": "Trainer / coach"
    },
    {
      "front": "Entrenamiento",
      "back": "Training / workout"
    },
    {
      "front": "Los hombros",
      "back": "Shoulders"
    },
    {
      "front": "Marihuanero",
      "back": "Pothead / weed smoker"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser saludable",
      "back": "To be healthy"
    },
    {
      "front": "Yo hago mis cejas",
      "back": "I do my eyebrows"
    },
    {
      "front": "Entonces",
      "back": "So / Then"
    },
    {
      "front": "Sin alcohol",
      "back": "Non-alcoholic"
    },
    {
      "front": "Papas fritas",
      "back": "French fries"
    },
    {
      "front": "Alitas BBQ",
      "back": "BBQ wings"
    },
    {
      "front": "Impopular",
      "back": "Unpopular"
    },
    {
      "front": "Popular",
      "back": "Popular"
    },
    {
      "front": "Pertenecer",
      "back": "To belong"
    },
    {
      "front": "Yo continúo aprendiendo",
      "back": "I continue learning"
    },
    {
      "front": "Los suburbios",
      "back": "The suburbs"
    },
    {
      "front": "Partido político",
      "back": "Political party"
    },
    {
      "front": "Demasiado",
      "back": "Too much / Too many"
    },
    {
      "front": "Dañado",
      "back": "Damaged"
    },
    {
      "front": "Musculoso",
      "back": "Muscular"
    },
    {
      "front": "Mis propósitos",
      "back": "My goals"
    },
    {
      "front": "Bravo",
      "back": "Angry / Mad"
    },
    {
      "front": "Molesto",
      "back": "Annoyed"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un rompimiento",
      "back": "A breakup"
    },
    {
      "front": "Significativo",
      "back": "Meaningful"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cada vez yo quiero comprarlos",
      "back": "Each time I want to buy them"
    },
    {
      "front": "Andar",
      "back": "To walk"
    },
    {
      "front": "Producir",
      "back": "To produce"
    },
    {
      "front": "Traducir",
      "back": "To translate"
    },
    {
      "front": "Conducir",
      "back": "To drive"
    },
    {
      "front": "Traer",
      "back": "To bring"
    },
    {
      "front": "Decir",
      "back": "To say / tell"
    },
    {
      "front": "Venir",
      "back": "To come"
    },
    {
      "front": "Querer",
      "back": "To want"
    },
    {
      "front": "Saber",
      "back": "To find out / to know"
    },
    {
      "front": "Poner",
      "back": "To put"
    },
    {
      "front": "Poder",
      "back": "To be able to"
    },
    {
      "front": "Hacer",
      "back": "To do / make"
    },
    {
      "front": "Tener",
      "back": "To have"
    },
    {
      "front": "Estar",
      "back": "To be (temporary)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser / ir",
      "back": "To be / to go"
    },
    {
      "front": "La mayoría",
      "back": "The majority"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser precavido",
      "back": "To be cautious"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un hombre mayor",
      "back": "An older man"
    },
    {
      "front": "Claro",
      "back": "Light"
    },
    {
      "front": "Oscuro",
      "back": "Dark"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cabello lacio",
      "back": "Straight hair (same as liso)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cabello liso",
      "back": "Straight hair"
    },
    {
      "front": "Cabello crespo",
      "back": "Curly hair"
    },
    {
      "front": "Llevar",
      "back": "To wear / to carry"
    },
    {
      "front": "La alcaldía",
      "back": "City hall"
    },
    {
      "front": "Doloroso",
      "back": "Painful"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una trenza",
      "back": "A braid"
    },
    {
      "front": "El bigote",
      "back": "Mustache"
    },
    {
      "front": "La barba",
      "back": "Beard"
    },
    {
      "front": "Labios pintados",
      "back": "Painted lips"
    },
    {
      "front": "La primavera",
      "back": "Spring"
    },
    {
      "front": "Mudarse",
      "back": "To move (house)"
    },
    {
      "front": "Mi prometido / mi prometida",
      "back": "My fiancé / fiancée"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un pavo rostizado",
      "back": "Roasted turkey"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un pavo horneado",
      "back": "Baked turkey"
    },
    {
      "front": "Puré de papa",
      "back": "Mashed potatoes"
    },
    {
      "front": "Vegetales",
      "back": "Vegetables"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un pavo",
      "back": "A turkey"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ir a pie",
      "back": "To go on foot"
    },
    {
      "front": "Estar cuerdo",
      "back": "To be sane"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ella vino el fin de semana",
      "back": "She came on the weekend"
    },
    {
      "front": "Definitivamente",
      "back": "Definitely"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser egoísta",
      "back": "To be selfish"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser generoso",
      "back": "To be generous"
    },
    {
      "front": "Tecnología",
      "back": "Technology"
    },
    {
      "front": "Joyas",
      "back": "Jewelry"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un carro lujoso",
      "back": "A luxury car"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ahorrar",
      "back": "To save money"
    },
    {
      "front": "Relajarse",
      "back": "To relax"
    },
    {
      "front": "Salir con amigos",
      "back": "To go out with friends"
    },
    {
      "front": "El coche",
      "back": "Car"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ser preciso",
      "back": "To be precise"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ir a la cama",
      "back": "To go to bed"
    },
    {
      "front": "Suficiente",
      "back": "Enough"
    },
    {
      "front": "¿Qué haces?",
      "back": "What are you doing?"
    },
    {
      "front": "¿Y tú?",
      "back": "And you?"
    },
    {
      "front": "¿Cómo estás?",
      "back": "How are you?"
    },
    {
      "front": "Yo no tengo",
      "back": "I don’t have"
    },
    {
      "front": "Yo tengo",
      "back": "I have"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un pocillo",
      "back": "A mug"
    },
    {
      "front": "Un teléfono",
      "back": "A phone"
    },
    {
      "front": "Rubio",
      "back": "Blonde"
    },
    {
      "front": "Negro",
      "back": "Black"
    },
    {
      "front": "Amarillo",
      "back": "Yellow"
    },
    {
      "front": "Verde",
      "back": "Green"
    },
    {
      "front": "Conejo",
      "back": "Rabbit"
    },
    {
      "front": "Balón",
      "back": "Ball"
    },
    {
      "front": "Gato",
      "back": "Cat"
    },
    {
      "front": "Perro",
      "back": "Dog"
    },
    {
      "front": "Carro",
      "back": "Car"
    },
    {
      "front": "Estrella",
      "back": "Star"
    },
    {
      "front": "Árbol",
      "back": "Tree"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ciento cincuenta",
      "back": "One hundred fifty"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una compañía",
      "back": "A company"
    },
    {
      "front": "Costar un ojo de la cara",
      "back": "To cost an arm and a leg"
    },
    {
      "front": "Desear",
      "back": "To desire / To wish"
    },
    {
      "front": "El deseo",
      "back": "Desire"
    },
    {
      "front": "Tirar la toalla",
      "back": "To give up"
    },
    {
      "front": "La contabilidad",
      "back": "Accounting"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una persona ahorrativa",
      "back": "A thrifty person"
    },
    {
      "front": "Calefacción",
      "back": "Heating"
    },
    {
      "front": "Gastos",
      "back": "Expenses"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ingresos",
      "back": "Income"
    },
    {
      "front": "El mismo trabajo",
      "back": "The same job"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una reunión",
      "back": "A meeting"
    },
    {
      "front": "Pagar",
      "back": "To pay"
    },
    {
      "front": "Relajado",
      "back": "Relaxed"
    },
    {
      "front": "Tranquilo",
      "back": "Calm / Quiet"
    },
    {
      "front": "Nervioso",
      "back": "Nervous"
    },
    {
      "front": "Ansioso",
      "back": "Anxious"
    },
    {
      "front": "Pobre",
      "back": "Poor"
    },
    {
      "front": "Rico",
      "back": "Rich / Delicious"
    },
    {
      "front": "Dividir",
      "back": "To divide / To split"
    },
    {
      "front": "La edad",
      "back": "Age"
    },
    {
      "front": "Una cita",
      "back": "A date / An appointment"
    },
    {
      "front": "Avena",
      "back": "Oatmeal"
    },
    {
      "front": "Hubo",
      "back": "There was / There were"
    },
    {
      "front": "Salir con alguien",
      "back": "To go out with someone / To date someone"
    },
    {
      "front": "Vacío",
      "back": "Empty"
    },
    {
      "front": "Lleno",
      "back": "Full"
    }
  ]
}